A Guide to the Papers of the Prince Edward County Free School 1963-1967
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- The Office of the Superintendent
  - Administrative Memo's and Correspondence
    - Memo's Sullivan February 1964 (Box-folder 18:4)
    - Memo's Sullivan March 1964 (Box-folder 18:5)
    - Memo's Sullivan April 1963 (Box-folder 18:6)
    - Memo's Sullivan May 1964 (Box-folder 18:7)
    - Memo's Sullivan June, August 1964 (Box-folder 18:8)
    - Memo's Sullivan No Date (Box-folder 18:9)
    - Memo's Sullivan No Date (Box-folder 18:10)
    - Correspondence Sullivan June-Aug 1963 (Box-folder 19:1)
    - Correspondence Sullivan Aug 27-31 '63 (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Correspondence Sullivan Sept 1963 (Box-folder 19:3)
    - Correspondence Sullivan Oct-Dec '63 (Box-folder 19:4)
    - Correspondence Sullivan Jan-Feb '64 (Box-folder 19:5)
    - Correspondence Sullivan 1964 (Box-folder 19:6)
    - Correspondence Sullivan n.d. (Box-folder 19:7)
    - Correspondence March 1964 (Box-folder 19:8)
    - Correspondence April 1964 (Box-folder 19:9)
    - Correspondence May 1964 (Box-folder 19:10)
    - July-August 1965 (Box-folder 19:11)
    - Bulletins # 1-10 (Box-folder 19:12)
    - Bulletins # 11-20 (Box-folder 19:13)
    - Bulletins # 21-25 (Box-folder 19:14)
    - School Calender 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19:15)
  - Correspondence
    General Correspondence, Arranged Chronologically.
    - Correspondence B August-October 1963 (Box-folder 20:1)
    - Correspondence B November 1963 (Box-folder 20:2)
    - Correspondence C September 1963 (Box-folder 20:3)
    - Correspondence D November-December 1963 (Box-folder 20:4)
    - Correspondence E Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:5)
    - Correspondence F Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:6)
    - Correspondence G Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:7)
    - Correspondence H Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:8)
    - Correspondence J Oct-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:9)
    - Correspondence K Aug-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:10)
    - Correspondence L Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:11)
    - Correspondence M Nov-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:12)
    - Correspondence N Sept-Nov 1963 (Box-folder 20:13)
    - Correspondence O Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:14)
    - Correspondence P Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:15)
    - Correspondence R Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:16)
    - Correspondence S 1959 (Box-folder 20:17)
    - Correspondence S Aug-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:18)
    - Correspondence T Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:19)
    - Correspondence T Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:20)
    - Correspondence W Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:21)
    - Correspondence Y Sept-Dec 1963 (Box-folder 20:22)
    - Correspondence A January 1964 (Box-folder 21:1)
    - Correspondence A February 1964 (Box-folder 21:2)
    - Correspondence A March-April 1964 (Box-folder 21:3)
    - Correspondence A May-June 1964 (Box-folder 21:4)
    - Correspondence A July-Aug 1964 (Box-folder 21:5)
    - Correspondence C Jan-July 1964 (Box-folder 21:6)
    - Correspondence D Jan-March 1964 (Box-folder 21:7)
    - Correspondence D April-May 1964 (Box-folder 21:8)
    - Correspondence E Feb-March 1964 (Box-folder 21:8)
    - Correspondence F Jan-Oct 1964 (Box-folder 21:10)
    - Correspondence G Jan-April 1964 (Box-folder 21:11)
    - Correspondence G May-Sept 1964 (Box-folder 21:12)
    - Correspondence H Jan- March 1964 (Box-folder 21:13)
    - Correspondence H April-Oct 1964 (Box-folder 21:14)
    - Correspondence J Jan-Sept 1964 (Box-folder 21:15)
    - Correspondence K Jan-July 1964 (Box-folder 22:1)
    - Correspondence L Jan-June 1964
    - Correspondence M Jan-March 1964 (Box-folder 22:3)
    - Correspondence M April-Aug 1964 (Box-folder 22:4)
    - Correspondence Mc Jan-May 1964 (Box-folder 22:5)
    - Correspondence Mc April-Sept 1964 (Box-folder 22:6)
    - Correspondence N Jan- Sept 1964 (Box-folder 22:7)
    - Correspondence P Jan-Feb 1964 (Box-folder 22:8)
    - Correspondence O Jan-May 1964 (Box-folder 22:9)
    - Correspondence P Jan-July 1964 (Box-folder 22:10)
    - Correspondence R Jan-March 1964 (Box-folder 22:11)
    - Correspondence Q 1964 (Box-folder 22:12)
    - Correspondence S Jan-April 1964 (Box-folder 22:13)
    - Correspondence S May-Sept 1964 (Box-folder 22:14)
    - Correspondence T Jan-Sept 1964 (Box-folder 22:15)
    - Correspondence U Jan-Aug 1964 (Box-folder 22:16)
    - Correspondence V 1964 (Box-folder 22:17)
    - Correspondence W Jan-March 1964 (Box-folder 22:18)
    - Correspondence W April-Aug 1964 (Box-folder 22:19)
    - Correspondence Y Jan-Aug 1964 (Box-folder 22:10)
  - Correspondence By Folder Heading
    Correspondence maintained by folder heading, arranged alphabetically and then chronologically within the folder.
    - American Friends Service Committee 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:1)
    - Bank Application Forms 1964 (Box-folder 23:2)
    - Berkeley Correspondence May 1964 (Box-folder 23:3)
    - Berkeley 1964 (Box-folder 23:4)
    - Berkeley June 1964 (Box-folder 23:5)
    - Book Companies 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:6)
    - Calender (Box-folder 23:7)
    - Editor- Farmville Herald 1964 (Box-folder 23:8)
    - Field Expense Report (Box-folder 23:9)
    - Mrs. Farmer 1964 (Box-folder 23:10)
    - Harmon Sydney 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:11)
    - Vanden Heuvel, William 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:12)
    - Kendrick, S.A. 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:13)
    - Letters from students Art and Design 1963 (Box-folder 23:14)
    - Marsh, M.C. 1964 (Box-folder 23:15)
    - Maynard, Thomas request 1964 (Box-folder 23:16)
    - Memorial Service JFK (Box-folder 23:17)
    - Metzenbaum, Howard 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 23:19)
    - National Education Association 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:20)
    - Pavlat, Gladys (Box-folder 23:21)
    - People That Handle Money (Box-folder 23:22)
    - Picot, J.R. (Box-folder 23:23)
    - Saletan, Alberta 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:24)
    - Scholarships Grants (Box-folder 23:25)
    - N.V. Sullivan- Personal 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:26)
    - Sullivan- surplus material 1963-1964 (Box-folder 23:27)
    - Bonded Vehicle Agreement (Box-folder 24:1)
    - John Theanor 1963-1964 (Box-folder 24:2)
    - Salaries (Box-folder 24:3)
    - Social Security and Va Taxes (Box-folder 24:4)
    - Transfer Status (Box-folder 24:5)
    - Surplus (Box-folder 24:6)
    - Surplus (Warehouse Invoices) 1963-1964 (Box-folder 24:7)
    - Vocational Agriculture (Box-folder 24:8)
    - Van Raekel, Byron 1963 (Box-folder 24:9)
    - Wheatly School 1963-1964 (Box-folder 24:10)
  - Personal Files
    Resumes of prospective employees of the Free School Association
    - Teacher Application (Box-folder 25:1)
    - Teacher Application D-M (Box-folder 25:2)
    - Teacher Application No-Z (Box-folder 25:3)
    - Teacher Confidential References (Box-folder 25:4)
    - Christine Irvine, Secretary (Box-folder 25:5)
    - Allen, Vera J.- Mary Branch #2 (Box-folder 25:6)
    - Anderson, Marion M.B. # 2 (Box-folder 25:7)
    - Barley, Etta Rose (Box-folder 25:8)
    - Barnes, Alva D. (Box-folder 25:9)
    - Barnhill, Josephine V. (Box-folder 25:10)
    - Barnes, Katherine W. - Moton (Box-folder 25:11)
    - Bellamy, Norieka- Worsham (Box-folder 25:12)
    - Bland, Lemuel C.- Moton (Box-folder 25:13)
    - Brown, Carolyn R.- M.B. #1 (Box-folder 25:14)
    - Burke, Nelson- Worsham (Box-folder 25:15)
    - Chandler, C.E. (Box-folder 25:16)
    - Coley, H.E.- M.B. # 2 (Box-folder 25:17)
    - Connelly, Mary Virginia- Moton (Box-folder 25:18)
    - Cooley, James B- Moton (Box-folder 25:29)
    - Cuffee, Clarence- Moton (Box-folder 25:20)
    - Curtis, James W. (Box-folder 25:21)
    - Cutler, Evelyn B.- M.B # 1 (Box-folder 25:22)
    - Darden, Mary M.- Branch # 2 (Box-folder 25:23)
    - DeMoss, Joseph D. (Box-folder 25:24)
    - Dennis, Marion W.- Worsham (Box-folder 25:25)
    - Dudley, Arthur (Box-folder 25:26)
    - Dudley, Letha (Box-folder 25:27)
    - Edgerton, Wilbert Delana- Moton (Box-folder 25:28)
    - Farrish, Demetris L. - M.B. # 1 (Box-folder 25:29)
    - Ferguson, Anna E. (Box-folder 25:30)
    - Franklin, Patsy C. (Box-folder 25:31)
    - Gwens, Emory (Box-folder 25:32)
    - Griffin, Adelaide P. (Box-folder 25:33)
    - Gordon, Doris- M.B. # 2 (Box-folder 25:34)
    - Hall, Freddie L. - Special Teacher (Box-folder 25:35)
    - Harding, Charlotte E. (Box-folder 25:36)
    - Harris, William L. (Box-folder 25:37)
    - Hartman, Sheila- M.B. # 1 (Box-folder 25:38)
    - Herndon, Ernestine- M.B. # 1 (Box-folder 25:39)
    - Holman (Box-folder 26:1)
    - Hoover (Box-folder 26:2)
    - Hosley (Box-folder 26:3)
    - Hubbard (Box-folder 26:4)
    - Jarrell, Charles (Box-folder 26:5)
    - Jeffreys, Vivian W. (Box-folder 26:6)
    - Jenkins, Emma (Box-folder 26:7)
    - Jiggette, Zypher Jones (Box-folder 26:8)
    - Johnson, Carrie Willis (Box-folder 26:9)
    - Johnson, Celestine H. (Box-folder 26:10)
    - Johnson, Norris (Box-folder 26:11)
    - Johnson, Oretha M. (Box-folder 26:12)
    - Johnson, Ruby (Box-folder 26:13)
    - Johnson, William E. (Box-folder 26:14)
    - Jones, Duane J. -Moton High School (Box-folder 26:15)
    - Jones, Gertrude (Box-folder 26:16)
    - Kelly, Alice - Worsham (Box-folder 26:17)
    - Kelly, Douglas Lee (Box-folder 26:18)
    - Leatherberry, Flossie Moran (Box-folder 26:19)
    - Lee, Catherine (Box-folder 26:20)
    - Lyte, Evelyn Joyce -Moton (Box-folder 26:21)
    - Madison, Mary W. (Box-folder 26:22)
    - Mayfield, Thomas- Moton (Box-folder 26:23)
    - McClure, Ellen Louise- Branch # 2 (Box-folder 26:25)
    - McCown, Beulah- Branch # 1 (Box-folder 26:26)
    - McKinney, John Wesley (Box-folder 26:27)
    - McPherson, Ethelyn Holden- Branch # 1 (Box-folder 26:28)
    - Merewether, Diane Genevieve- Moton High School (Box-folder 26:29)
    - McLean, Leila - Worsham (Box-folder 26:30)
    - Mielke, Phylliss- Mary E. Branch # 2 (Box-folder 26:31)
    - Mitchell, Beatrice N. - Moton (Box-folder 26:32)
    - Mitchell, Grafton (Box-folder 26:33)
    - Mizzell, Iannie S. (Box-folder 26:34)
    - Monroe, Adele- Moton Clerical (Box-folder 26:35)
    - Moore, Ella B. - Moton Cafeteria (Box-folder 26:36)
    - Morgan, Barbara Jeannette- Moton High School (Box-folder 26:37)
    - Morris, Mamie C.R. (Box-folder 26:38)
    - Morton, Alton (Box-folder 26:39)
    - Nimmo, Melvia Hunter (Box-folder 26:40)
    - Packer, Woodrow- Moton (Box-folder 26:41)
    - Page, Yvonne A. (Box-folder 26:42)
    - Poseur, Roberta S. (Box-folder 26:43)
    - Pena, Marjorie- Moton (Box-folder 26:44)
    - Pena, Robert Joseph- Moton High School (Box-folder 26:45)
    - Pollard, Barbara Bell (Box-folder 26:46)
    - Pruden, Famie S. - Moton High School (Box-folder 26:47)
    - Edgerton, Wilbert D. - Moton (Box-folder 27:1)
    - Ragland, James F Jr. - Moton (Box-folder 27:2)
    - Rawlins, Sylvia M. _ Mary E. Branch # 2 (Box-folder 27:3)
    - Raynor, Mary G.- Mary E. Branch # 2 (Box-folder 27:4)
    - Ricks, Hannah B. - Worsham (Box-folder 27:5)
    - Roberts, Francis - Worsham (Box-folder 27:6)
    - Samuel, Avista- Moton (Box-folder 27:7)
    - Satow, Hannah C. - Mary E. Branch # 1 (Box-folder 27:8)
    - Saunders, Judith Ann- Moton (Box-folder 27:9)
    - Shipp, Madge E. - Moton (Box-folder 27:10)
    - Smith, Lonnese Jr. (Box-folder 27:11)
    - Sullivan, Martha R. - Worsham (Box-folder 27:12)
    - Taylor, Ervin J. - Moton (Box-folder 27:13)
    - Tennant, Elizabeth- Worsham (Box-folder 27:14)
    - Thompson, Edna C. (Box-folder 27:15)
    - Thompson, Samuel Ray (Box-folder 27:16)
    - Tignor, Aliva B.- Branch # 1 (Box-folder 27:17)
    - Tillman, Helen W. - Mary E. Branch # 1 (Box-folder 27:18)
    - Turner,Virginia S. (Box-folder 27:20)
    - Tyson, Dana Katherine - Worsham (Box-folder 27:21)
    - Van Bens, Albert D.- Moton (Box-folder 27:22)
    - Wacker, Phyllis G. (Box-folder 27:23)
    - Wagstaff, Carolyn - Mary E. Branch # 1 (Box-folder 27:24)
    - Walton, Mary B. - Mary E. Branch # 2 (Box-folder 27:25)
    - Walton, William W. (Box-folder 27:26)
    - Watson, Harold L. - Moton (Box-folder 27:27)
    - Watson, Willie Mae- Mary E. Branch # 2 (Box-folder 27:28)
    - Weitzenfield, Julian S. - Moton (Box-folder 27:29)
    - Welchell, Brond R. - Moton (Box-folder 27:30)
    - White, James A. - Worsham (Box-folder 27:31)
    - Whittaker, Katharine W. - Moton High School (Box-folder 27:32)
    - Wiggins, James A. - Worsham (Box-folder 27:33)
    - Wilkerson, Louise- Mary E. Branch E. Branch #1 (Box-folder 27:34)
    - Williams, Evelyn F. - School Nurse (Box-folder 27:35)
    - Williams, Gloria T.- Moton (Box-folder 27:36)
    - Williams, James- Mary E. Branch # 1 (Box-folder 27:37)
    - Wiley, Esther L. - Moton (Box-folder 27:38)
    - Wilkins, Julia- Moton (Box-folder 27:39)
    - Wilson, Ethel W. (Box-folder 27:40)
    - Womack, Flossie I. - Mary E. Branch (Box-folder 27:41)
    - Womack, Ophelia (Box-folder 27:42)
  - Exit Interviews
    Views of personnel regarding their experience working in the free school, included are some of their recommendations for improvement as observed by them.
    - Exit Question- Future Addresser of B#1, B#2, Worsham, and Moton (1) (Box-folder 28:1)
    - Exit Question- Future Addresser of B #1, B#2, Worsham, and Moton (2) (Box-folder 28:2)
    - Exit- Housing (white) (Box-folder 28:3)
    - Exite Question 1964 (1) (Box-folder 28:4)
    - Exit Question 1964 (2) (Box-folder 28:5)
    - Exit Question 1964 (3) (Box-folder 28:6)
    - Exit Questions Robert Moton 1964 (1) (Box-folder 28:7)
    - Exit Question Robert Moton (2) (Box-folder 28:8)
    - Exit Question Br #2 (Box-folder 28:9)
  - Student Evaluations
    Student views of their experience in the Free School. Comments concern instruction, facilities, and their thoughts on the future.
    - Student Evaluation Oct 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:1)
    - Student Evaluation Oct 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:2)
    - Student Evaluation Oct 7, 963 (Box-folder 29:3)
    - Student Evaluation Nov 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:4)
    - Student Evaluation Nov 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:5)
    - Student Evaluation Nov 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:6)
    - Student Evaluation Nov 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:7)
    - Student Evaluation Nov 7, 1963 (Box-folder 29:8)
    - Student Reaction Report (Box-folder 29:9)
- Administrative Offices of the Free School System
  - The Principals Office
    The organization of the Free School System was divided into four administrative groups. The largest numbers of students were assigned to the high school. Office Correspondence maintained by the Principal, is arranged by alphabet and then chronologically within the folder. Correspondence addresses a wide range of topics, employment, administrative problems, and the problems of running a high school on a day-to-day basis.
    - American Education Week November 1963 (Box-folder 30:1)
    - Audio-Visual Aids 1963-1964 (Box-folder 30:2)
    - Absentee Oct 1963 (Box-folder 30:3)
    - Absentee Nov 1963 (Box-folder 30:4)
    - Absentee Dec 1963 (Box-folder 30:5)
    - Absentee Jan 1963 (Box-folder 30:6)
    - Absentees April 1963 (Box-folder 30:8)
    - Absentee March 1963 (Box-folder 30:9)
    - Absentee May 1963 (Box-folder 30:10)
    - Absentee June 1963 (Box-folder 30:11)
    - Absentee July 1963 (Box-folder 30:12)
    - Absentee Aug 1963 (Box-folder 30:13)
    - Assembly Programs Nov 1963-June 1964 (Box-folder 30:14)
    - Books 1963-1964 (Box-folder 30:15)
    - Business Management Office Nov-Dec 1963- Feb 1964 (Box-folder 30:16)
    - Business Management Office- Cooley Office Moton (Box-folder 30:17)
    - Class Enrollment (Box-folder 30:18)
    - Clothing (Box-folder 30:19)
    - Conference Expenses Cooley 1964 (Box-folder 30:20)
    - Cooley-Sullivan Correspondence Jan 3, 1964- March 1964 (Box-folder 30:21)
    - Cooley-Sullivan Correspondence April-May 1964 (Box-folder 30:22)
    - Cooley-Sullivan Correspondence June-July 1964 (Box-folder 30:23)
    - Correspondence (Parents) 1964 (Box-folder 30:24)
    - Correspondence Confidential 1964 (Box-folder 30:25)
    - Correspondence Miscellaneous 1964 (Box-folder 30:26)
    - General Correspondence (R.R.Moton) 1964 (Box-folder 30:27)
    - Memo's from Mr. J.B. Cooley (Box-folder 31:1)
    - Correspondence- Mr. Thomas L. Maynard Assistant Principal (Box-folder 31:2)
    - Teachers Sheets (Box-folder 31:3)
    - Correspondence A 1964 (Box-folder 31:4)
    - Correspondence B 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:5)
    - Correspondence C 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:6)
    - Correspondence D 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:7)
    - Correspondence E 31:8 (Box-folder 31:8)
    - Correspondence F 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:9)
    - Correspondence G 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:10)
    - Correspondence H 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:11)
    - Correspondence J 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:12)
    - Correspondence K 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:13)
    - Correspondence L 1963 (Box-folder 31:8)
    - Correspondence M 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:15)
    - Correspondence Mc 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:16)
    - Correspondence N 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:17)
    - Correspondence P 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:18)
    - Correspondence Q 1964 (Box-folder 31:19)
    - Correspondence R 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:20)
    - Correspondence S 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:21)
    - Correspondence T 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:22)
    - Correspondence U 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:23)
    - Correspondence V 1964 (Box-folder 31:24)
    - Correspondence W 1963-1964 (Box-folder 31:25)
    - Correspondence XYZ 1963 (Box-folder 31:26)
    - Substitute Teachers (Box-folder 31:27)
    - Teachers Schedules and Room Assignments (Cooley) (Box-folder 31:28)
  - Department Correspondence
    Correspondence and reports from the other administrative units in the Prince Edward County Free School System.
    - Education 1963 (Box-folder 32:1)
    - Faculty Breakdown 1964 (Box-folder 32:2)
    - Field Trip 1964 (Box-folder 32:3)
    - Field Trip Expense 1964 (Box-folder 32:4)
    - Field Trip Special 1963-1964 (Box-folder 32:5)
    - Field Trip Special (Box-folder 32:6)
    - First Nine Weeks Grading Period (Box-folder 32:7)
    - Freight Bill 1963 (Box-folder 32:8)
    - Grading Scale (Box-folder 32:9)
    - Guidance Counselor- R.R. Moton (Box-folder 32:10)
    - Holly Knoll Leadership Retreat 1966-1967 (Box-folder 32:11)
    - Honor Roll (Box-folder 32:12)
    - Housing Commencement and Conference 1964-1965 (Box-folder 32:13)
    - Inform others on Teachers Confidential 1964 (Box-folder 32:14)
    - Library 1963-1964 (Box-folder 32:15)
    - Library 1964 (Box-folder 32:16)
    - Library 1964 (Box-folder 32:17)
    - Locker Assignment (Box-folder 32:18)
    - Memo's 1964 (Box-folder 32:19)
    - Memo's 1963-1964 (Box-folder 32:20)
    - Menu's 1964 (Box-folder 32:12)
    - Physical Education 1963 (Box-folder 32:22)
    - Prince Edward Free School Association 1963-1964 (Box-folder 32:23)
    - Publishing Companies 1964 (Box-folder 32:24)
    - Student Evaluation Reaction Report 1963 (Box-folder 32:25)
    - Substitute Teachers (Box-folder 32:26)
    - Teachers Schedules and Room Assignments (Box-folder 32:27)
  - Department Reports
    Most of the units were required to submit a final report for thier units at the end of the school year. This subseries documents the activities of those departments for the school year 1965 to 1965.
    - Annual Report on Speech Hearing (Box-folder 33:1)
    - Clinical Statistical Reports (Box-folder 33:2)
    - Final Annual Report (Box-folder 33:3)
    - Health Committee Reports (Box-folder 33:4)
    - Dr. Kendrick's Report (Box-folder 33:5)
    - R.R. Moton Roster (Box-folder 33:6)
    - Preliminary Annual Report (Box-folder 33:7)
    - Purchase Order (Box-folder 33:8)
    - Scholarships and Loans (Box-folder 33:9)
    - School Nurse/Health Reports (Box-folder 33:10)
    - School Nurse/ Health Reports (Box-folder 33:11)
    - School Philosophy (Box-folder 33:12)
    - State Board on Education (Box-folder 33:13)
    - Student Listing and Correspondence (Box-folder 33:14)
    - Students Listing and Correspondence (Box-folder 33:15)
    - Summer Reports (Box-folder 33:16)
    - Summer School drop Out 1964 (Box-folder 33:17)
    - Suspension and Expulsions (Box-folder 33:18)
    - Teachers (Box-folder 33:19)
    - Teacher Absence (Box-folder 33:20)
    - Teachers Addresses (Box-folder 33:21)
    - Teachers Monthly Report to Principal (Box-folder 33:22)
    - Teachers of 9-12 year old groups (Box-folder 33:23)
    - Teaching Units (Box-folder 33:24)
    - Townsend, Wallace (Box-folder 33:25)
    - Virginia's Teachers Classification (Box-folder 33:26)
    - Virginian 20th Century (Box-folder 33:27)
    - Walton, William (other materials) (Box-folder 33:28)
- Literary
  - Reports
    These reports were generated to inform those involved with the status of the free school. Amongst the reports is a final report issued by the superintendent. In addition there are also a number of progress reports from both the office of the superintendent and some of the other programs being provided at The Prince Edward County Free School.
    - Progress Report November 1964 (Box-folder 33A:1)
    - Progress Report January 1st, 1964 (Box-folder 33A:2)
    - Progress Report August 6, 1964 (Box-folder 33A:3)
    - Progress Report- Art (Box-folder 33A:4)
    - Progress Report- Science (Box-folder 33A:5)
    - Progress Report- Transportation (Box-folder 33A:7)
    - Progress Report- Special Report (Box-folder 33A:8)
    - Progress Report- Music (Box-folder 33A:9)
    - After School Activities- Field Trip (Box-folder 33A:10)
    - Final Progress Report August 6, 1964 (Box-folder 33A:11)
  - Speeches
    Neil Sullivan and others were called upon to speak before a number of associations and groups concerning the progress of the free school.
    - Sullivan Speech- VTA Convention November 1, 1963 (Box-folder 33A:12)
    - Sullivan Speech- VFPT Annual Convention December 7, 1963 (Box-folder 33A:13)
    - Sullivan Speech-Memorial For John Fitzgerald Kennedy December 13, 1963 (Box-folder 33A:14)
    - Sullivan Speech- The NAACP Annual Convention June 26, 1964 (Box-folder 33A:15)
    - Sullivan Speech- The ATA National Convention July 28, 1964 (Box-folder 33A: 16)
    - Sullivan Speech- The VTA April 11, 1964 (Box-folder 33A: 17)
    - Sullivan Speech- N.C.S.P.S. May 18, 1964 (Box-folder 33A:18)
    - Sullivan Speech- No Date No Place of Presentation (Box-folder 33A:19)
    - Dudley Speech May 31st, 1964 (Box-folder 33A:20)
    - Paper-Clarence Cuffee (Box-folder 33A:21)
  - Writings
    Policy Manuals for the Prince Edward County Free School, and several school divisions outside of Virginia.
    - Willie Mae Watson "About Prince Edward" February 1964 (Box-folder 33A:22)
    - Sullivan-Operations Manual (Box-folder 33:23)
    - Sullivan- Manual For Teachers 1962-1963
    - Sullivan- Handbook for Teachers 1963
- Office of Pupil Personnel
  - Correspondence
    - Audio Visual Correspondence 1963 (Box-folder 34:1)
    - Audio Visual Correspondence 1964 (Box-folder 34:2)
    - Audio Visual Meeting Memo's (Box-folder 34:3)
    - Curriculum Guidelines (Box-folder 34:4)
    - Guidelines for curriculum development (Box-folder 34:5)
    - Curriculum Notes # 1 (Box-folder 34:6)
    - Guidance (Box-folder 34:7)
    - Transcripts Needed (Guidance) (Box-folder 34:8)
    - Survey's of 1953,1954,1958-1959 Guidance (Box-folder 34:9)
    - Students in Danger of failing for the year (Guidance) (Box-folder 34:10)
    - Curriculum Notes- Miss Watson (Box-folder 34:11)
    - Memo's from Miss W.M.Watson (Box-folder 34:12)
    - Information on Standardized Tests (Guidance) (Box-folder 34:13)
    - Confidential Financial Statements (Guidance) (Box-folder 34:14)
    - Speech and Hearing Therapy (Box-folder 34:15)
    - Vocational Education (Box-folder 34:16)
    - Health (Box-folder 34:17)
    - Form 942 a (Box-folder 35:1)
    - Form Accumulated Contribution (Box-folder 35:2)
    - Forms Certificate of Teachers Absences (Box-folder 35:3)